Summary

I'm a professional Web Developer who has been in the business since 1999. During my career, I've worked for many interactive agencies on brands such as Microsoft, Virgin, Xbox, Ford, Land Rover, BT, and Cohn & Wolfe.

I have a good eye for detail and an interest in building high quality user interfaces. I have a wide range of skills that cover both front and backend development. I like to learn and experiment with new technologies, and I have good analytical and problem solving skills.

Skills

- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, LESS, BEM, OOCSS
- CSS Animations, Velocity
- JavaScript, ES6, OOP, AngularJS, jQuery, RequireJS
- TDD/BDD, Jasmine, Karma
- Modernizr, D3, Google Maps API
- Grunt, Gulp, Webpack, Browserify
- Babel, Bower, NPM/NVM
- Web Standards, Accessibility, ARIA

- Progressive Enhancement
- Mobile First, Responsive Web Design
- AEM/CQ5, Jekyll, WordPress
- Drupal, OpenCart, ESDoc
- Bash, Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP, RegEx
- Git, GitFlow, SVN, JIRA
- Vagrant, VirtualBox
- Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch

Experience

Senior Web Developer

AnalogFolk, Nov 2015 - Apr 2016 (6 months)

Worked in an Agile team to develop front-end components for a hybrid mobile banking app. Developed to web standards with attention to semantic html and accessibility. Components were presented as part of a living style guide generated with Jekyll and ESDoc.

- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, BEM
- JavaScript, ES6, Jasmine, TDD/BDD
- Jekyll, ESDoc, Gulp, Webpack, Babel, Karma, Git, GitFlow, JIRA

Senior Web Developer

VCCP, October 2015 (2 weeks)

www.chimegroup.com

Brought in to complete an ongoing project in time for launch. Worked to tight deadlines to ensure templates matched responsive designs and worked across browsers and mobile devices.

- HTML5, CSS3, LESS, Bootstrap
- JavaScript, jQuery, WordPress
- · Gulp, Git, JIRA

Interactive Web Developer

VML London, February 2015 - May 2015 (4 months, 1 extension)

www.virginactive.co.uk

Worked on two projects. The first, in a small team building a responsive, single page app. It featured navigational map and timeline components built with Google Maps and D3 respectively. The second, working in a large Agile team on a responsive website redesign for Virgin Active.

- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, BEM, Foundation
- JavaScript, AngularJS, Google Maps API, D3
- · Grunt, Git, JIRA

Web Developer

Pixelgroup, November 2014 - December 2014 (5 weeks)

Developed the main interface of an online gaming app; a fluid width/height design built with AngularJS and Velocity.

- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, BEM
- · JavaScript, AngularJS, Velocity
- Grunt, Bower, Git

Interactive Web Developer

VML London, March 2014 - October 2014 (8 months, 1 extension)

www.premierinn.com

Worked as part of a large team in a test driven, Agile environment. Developed user interfaces for CMS websites built on the AEM/CQ5 platform. Maintained a living style guide to demonstrate and document UI components.

- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, BEM
- JavaScript, AngularJS, AEM/CQ5
- Vagrant, SVN, JIRA

Interactive Web Developer

VML London, November 2013 - January 2014 (2 months, 1 extension)

Developed a responsive, content aggregation site for an online campaign. Used the Isotope library for the main view layout. Built to be cross-browser compatible on both desktop and mobile devices.

- HTML5, CSS3, Sass, OOCSS
- JavaScript, jQuery, RequireJS, Isotope
- SVN, JIRA

Web Developer

Critical Mass, April 2013 - July 2013 (4 months, 2 extensions)

Worked as a senior member of a team building a large multi-lingual website. Developed the front-end templates for an e-commerce site, ready for integration into a Java Spring framework.

- HTML5, CSS3, LESS, OOCSS
- · JavaScript, jQuery
- Git, JIRA

Other Positions

Project Manager / Web Developer

Digital Vision, January 2002 - February 2005

Lead Developer

AQKA, July 1999 - June 2001

Education

Humberside University, Hull

BSc Mechanical Engineering and Manufacturing Systems, 1995 – 1999

Languages

Spanish (limited working proficiency).